So if the insurance of your bike or scooter has
expired and you
want to get a new insurance, then let us
see the complete process.  How to
take, buy, purchase insurance using PhonePe app from your mobile phone.
What to do for this?  You have to
open the PhonePe app on your mobile.
After opening the PhonePe app,
go to the search section and search for
bike insurance.  If you search for a bike,
this bike insurance will be visible.
This has to be selected.  If you have
purchased bike insurance earlier,
you will see it here.  If it has expired then
you can resume the same insurance.
Rest here you
see Insure Another Bike.  After tapping on this,
you can take new bike insurance from the beginning.
And if you have
not already taken any bike insurance from the PhonePe app, then you will see this type of interface.
Here you have to enter your bike
number and submit it.
After that, a page will open here to select the plan.
So here you have to
tap on it to select the plan.
Here you can select third party or
comprehensive plan.
Third party covers the damage caused to the person in
front by your bike or scooter.  It happens to the
property of the person in front.  Whereas
in comprehensive, damage to your bike will also be covered.
Damage to the bike or scooter and
also to the property of the other person
is covered.  So it happens to both of them.
To avoid having to pay any fine, you must opt ​​for a comprehensive plan.
After that, from here you will
select the duration as per your requirement.  How long should the
plan be taken?  I will select one year here.
After that, if you
want to take personal accidental cover,
you will turn it on but due to this the
premium value increases.  However, even if
you do not take personal accidental cover, it will still work.
You just need to have a comprehensive plan.
After that, plans of different companies will be
visible here and the IDV of each plan will
also be visible.  IDB stands for
Insured Declared Value.   The
maximum value of your bike that the
insurance company can pay you in case of total loss or
theft of the bike.  So
you have to see how much amount you pay and how much ID is given to you by different companies.  You have to
select it accordingly.  So I choose this one,
SBI General Insurance.
After selecting your plan accordingly,
you can enter the details of your previous insurance here.
If you do
not remember the details of your previous insurance, you can turn it on.
Otherwise, if you remember, you can
enter the expiry date of the previous policy.  That means, the
date of whatever bike insurance or scooter insurance was running before this has to be entered.  When did it expire, its
expiry date and the name of the previous insurance company have to be
entered here.  Its
policy number has to be entered.  Did you make a
claim in the previous insurance or
not?  You can select yes or no as per your
convenience.  If you have
not made a claim in the previous insurance, then
you can get the bonus here by selecting No.
You have to select the maximum percentage here.
Whatever option you get,
select it and continue from here.
After that you will
see all the details here.  Policy Details,
Previous Policy Details, Bike Details.  Here the
total amount that you have to pay will be
visible.  By clicking on this you
can see specifically how much charge is being
taken for what.
After that, click on Buy Plan here.
After that you will have to make payment here.
You can make payment through UPI or you
can make payment through credit card, debit card.  I want to pay here using UPI.  I
will tap Pay and
then enter the UPI PIN and
approve the payment.  Now the owner details page will
open.  Here you have to
enter the PAN card number of the owner of the bike.  That means the
PAN card number of the person in whose name the bike is registered has to be entered.  The date of birth of
that person has to be entered.  The name of that person will
appear here and the email ID has to be
entered here and submitted.  After that,
identity proof will have to be uploaded here.  You will
select the ID type here.  Aadhar
Card, Driving License, Passport or
Voter ID Card as per your requirement.  So
here I selected Aadhar card.
After that the front and back side of the Aadhar card has to be
uploaded.  Click on the picture and
enter the full name.  Aadhaar Card on Edge.
Last four digits of Aadhar card have to be
entered.  Aadhar card has to be entered here on date of birth age.
And
enter the address.  You have to type everything like city state, pin code
and proceed.
After that the page with additional details will open.   You have to
select the gender here.  Father's
name has to be entered.  Marital status has to be
selected.  Married or unmarried,
these three have to be selected.  After that the
nominee also has to be selected.  First of all,
in the related person, you have to select
what is your relation with the person whom you want to make a nominee.  The
minimum age of the nominee should be 18 years.
After that, scroll down and
enter the name of the concerned person i.e. nominee
and proceed from here.
After that you have to capture a selfie here.
Capture a photo live and submit it.
After that this type of page will open.  Currently
KYC verification is in progress.  And
here you will see the insurance details.
Issue date, which plan
is selected, what is the IDV, vehicle details, owner
details, premium paid,
all these things will be visible to you here.  If
you ever open the PhonePe app and
go to search here and
search for bike insurance and
come to bike insurance, then it will be
visible to you in My Policies here.  You
can see that KYC details have been submitted.
As soon as the verification is complete, the
policy is instantly sent to your email ID.
So after waiting for some time,
you can see that
it has been activated here in My Policy.  Now I can
tap on this and download the policy document from here
or I can also get it sent to my email.  The
rest of it also
comes automatically on email.  To download,
tap on download and in this way you
can open it in any PDF viewer and your policy document gets opened.
You can also take a printout of it and
keep it.